indie-music.com 2010-02-09

# - Indie-Music.com

COMMITMENT TO YOUR PRIVACY 

This site is owned and operated by Indie-Music.com, Inc. Your privacy on the Internet is of the utmost importance to us. At Indie-Music.com, we want to make your experience online satisfying and safe. 

Because we gather certain types of information about our users, we feel you should fully understand the terms and conditions surrounding the capture and use of that information. This privacy statement discloses what information we gather and how we use it. 

INFORMATION INDIE-MUSIC.COM GATHERS AND TRACKS 

Indie-Music.com gathers three types of information about users: 

  * Information that users provide through optional, voluntary submissions. These are voluntary submissions to receive our electronic newsletters, to submit a site or artist for review, to participate in our message boards or forums, to email a friend, and from participation in polls and surveys.

  * Information Indie-Music.com gathers through aggregated tracking information derived mainly by tallying page views throughout our sites. This information allows us to better tailor our content to readers' needs and to help our advertisers and sponsors better understand the demographics of our audience. Because Indie-Music.com derives its revenue partly from sponsorships and advertising, providing such aggregated demographic data is essential to keeping our service free to users. Under no circumstances does Indie-Music.com divulge any information about an individual user to a third party.

  * Indie-Music.com Customers. For our subscribers and paying customers, Indie-Music.com collects only the neccesary information to administer an account, such as name, mailing address, billing information, and email address.

Indie-Music.com Gathers User Information In The Following Processes: 

Optional Voluntary Information 

We offer the following free services, which require some type of voluntary submission of personal information by users: 

1\. Electronic newsletters (Dispatches) 

We will offer a free electronic newsletter to users. Indie-Music.com gathers the email addresses of users who voluntarily subscribe or who submit a website for inclusion in Indie-Music.com's link sections. Users may remove themselves from this mailing list by following the link provided in every newsletter that points users to the subscription management page. 

2\. "E-mail this to a friend" Service 

Our site users can choose to electronically forward a link, page, or documents to someone else by clicking "e-mail this to a friend". The user must provide their email address, as well as that of the recipient. This information is used only in the case of transmission errors and, of course, to let the recipient know who sent the email. The information is not used for any other purpose. 

3\. Polling 

We may offer interactive polls to users so they can easily share their opinions with other users and see what our audience thinks about important issues. Opinions or other responses to polls are aggregated and are not identifiable to any particular user. Indie-Music.com may use a system to "tag" users after they have voted, so they can vote only once on a particular question. This tag is not correlated with information about individual users. 

4\. Surveys

Indie-Music.com may occasionally conduct user surveys to better target our content to our audience. We sometimes share the aggregated demographic information in these surveys with our sponsors, advertisers and partners. We never share any of this information about specific individuals with any third party. 

Children 

We will never knowingly request personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13 without requesting parental consent. 

Usage tracking 

On our freely available websites, Indie-Music.com tracks user traffic patterns throughout our network of sites. However, we do not correlate this information with data about individual users. Indie-Music.com does break down overall usage statistics according to a user's domain name, browser type, and MIME type by reading this information from the browser string (information contained in every user's browser). 

Indie-Music.com sometimes tracks and catalogs the search terms that users enter in our Search function, but this tracking is never associated with individual users. We use tracking information to determine which areas of our sites users like and don't like based on traffic to those areas. We do not track what individual users read, but rather how well each page performs overall. This helps us continue to build a better service for you. 

Members, Customers, or paid subscribers are logged if they access their personal account, however Indie-Music.com does not aggregate this information. It is stored strictly as a security measure for private Member data.

Cookies 

We may place a text file called a "cookie" in the browser files of your computer. The cookie itself does not contain Personal Information although it will enable us to relate your use of this site to information that you have specifically and knowingly provided. But the only personal information a cookie can contain is information you supply yourself. A cookie can't read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites. Indie-Music.com may use cookies to track user traffic patterns (as described above). Our advertising system may deliver a one-time cookie to better track ad impressions and click rates. 

You can refuse cookies by turning them off in your browser. If you've set your browser to warn you before accepting cookies, you will receive the warning message with each cookie. You do not need to have cookies turned on to use this site. However, you may need cookies to participate actively in polling, surveys, and other features, or to access your paid member account.

We also use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [click here](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).

USE OF INFORMATION 

Indie-Music.com uses any information voluntarily given by our users to enhance their experience in our network of sites, whether to provide interactive or personalized elements on the sites or to better prepare future content based on the interests of our users. As stated above, we use information that users voluntarily provide in order to send out electronic newsletters and to enable users to participate in polls, surveys, message boards, forums, and other registered user features. We send out newsletters to subscribers on a regular schedule (depending on the newsletter), and occasionally send out special editions when we think subscribers might be particularly interested in something we are doing. 

We use tracking information to determine which areas of our sites users like and don't like based on traffic to those areas. We do not track what individual users read, but rather how well each page performs overall. This helps us continue to build a better service for you. We track search terms entered in Search function as one of many measures of what interests our users. But we don't track which terms a particular user enters. 

Indie-Music.com creates aggregate reports on user demographics and traffic patterns for advertisers, sponsors and partners. This allows our advertisers to advertise more effectively, and allows our users to receive advertisements that are pertinent to their needs. Because we don't track the usage patterns of individual users, an advertiser or sponsor will never know that a specific user clicked their ad. We will not disclose any information about any individual user except to comply with applicable law or valid legal process or to protect the personal safety of our users or the public. 

We also use the contact and billing information of paid Subscribers/Members to administer their monthly accounts.

SHARING OF THE INFORMATION 

Indie-Music.com uses the above-described information to tailor our content to suit your needs and help our advertisers better understand our audience's demographics. This is essential to keeping our free service free, as well as offering the best value for our paid customers. We will not share information about individual users with any third party, except to comply with applicable law or valid legal process or to protect the personal safety of our users or the public. 

Indie-Music.com never shares newsletter mailing lists, customer information, or private data of any sort with any third parties, including advertisers, sponsors or partners. 

We use third-party credit card payment processing services, which may require personal information to be passed to the processing company. Our payment processing companies (Wells-Fargo, Authorize.net, and [Paypal](http://www.paypal.com/)) are also strongly committed to your online privacy.

SECURITY 

Indie-Music.com operates secure data networks protected by industry standard protection systems. Our security and privacy policies are periodically reviewed and enhanced as necessary and only authorized individuals have access to the information provided by our customers. 

OPT-OUT POLICY 

We give users options wherever necessary and practical. Such choices include: 

  * Opting not to add a website link, or to subscribe to our electronic newsletters. 
  * Opting not to participate in certain interactive areas, which completely alleviates the need to gather any personally identifiable information from our users 

YOUR CONSENT 

By using this site, you consent to the collection and use of this information by Indie-Music.com. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it. 

COPYRIGHT ISSUES

Who do I contact if I suspect a copyright violation?

Indie-Music.com does not tolerate copyright infringement and aggressively police our site for any violations. We investigate all allegations of infringement and immediately remove any content determined to be infringing under the DMCA. 

To report an issue for investigation, please include the following information: 

Content in question  
URL link pointing to the content  
Your complete contact information  
Information regarding the alleged infringement. 

And snail mail it to: 

Indie-Music.com  
ATTN: COPYRIGHT  
PO Box 78036  
Indianapolis, IN 46278

For more details on the information required for valid notification, see 17 U.S.C. 512(c)(3). 

You should be aware that, under the DCMA, claimants who make misrepresentations concerning copyright infringement may be liable for damages incurred as a result of the removal or blocking of the material, court costs, and attorneys fees.
